[
  {
    "question": "Who is oryx' son?",
    "correctAnswer": "Crota",
    "wrongAnswer": "Malok",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Alak-Hul",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the ice Breaker?",
    "correctAnswer": "An exotic sniper",
    "wrongAnswer": "A legendary sniper",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "A raid sniper",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Exotics"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Destiny, what planet does the moon belong to?",
    "correctAnswer": "Earth",
    "wrongAnswer": "Venus",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Mars",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which Exotic was **NOT** part of Xûr's first ever inventory?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gjallahorn",
    "wrongAnswer": "Red Death",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Sunbreakers",
    "grade": "Hard",
    "tag": "Exotics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following gods wasn't a main Hive god?",
    "correctAnswer": "Zi Arack",
    "wrongAnswer": "Sathone",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Auryx",
    "grade": "Hard",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "When detected, how long do you have to kill a Gorgon in the Vault of Glass?",
    "correctAnswer": "10 seconds",
    "wrongAnswer": "5 seconds",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "15 seconds",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Mechanic"
  },
  {
    "question": "What event nearly caused the extinction of the human race?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Collapse",
    "wrongAnswer": "The End of Time",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Reckoning",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "When was the darkness created",
    "correctAnswer": "At the beginning of time",
    "wrongAnswer": "Before the beginning of time",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "After the beginning of time",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who practices a religion known as Sword Logic?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Hive",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Traveler",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Eris Morn",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is the Black Garden Located?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mars",
    "wrongAnswer": "Earth",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Venus",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Locations"
  },
  {
    "question": "What part of the Vex is biological?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mind-core fluid",
    "wrongAnswer": "Brain",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Eyes",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the ghosts?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Traveler",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Speaker",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Guardians",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the Nine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dark Matter Beings",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Vex Minds",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Fallen Primes",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wielded the Thorn originally?",
    "correctAnswer": "Dredgen Yor",
    "wrongAnswer": "Uldren Sov",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Lord Felwinter",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What came before the Collapse?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Golden Age",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Dark Age",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "New Beginning",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the Fallen call themselves in their own language?",
    "correctAnswer": "Eliksni",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Fallen",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Scorn",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many exotic weapons does Destiny have?",
    "correctAnswer": "45",
    "wrongAnswer": "46",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "44",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Exotics"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is not a representitve of the vanguard?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lord Shaxx",
    "wrongAnswer": "Ikora Rey",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Zavala",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Destiny's code name when it was being developped?",
    "correctAnswer": "Project Tiger",
    "wrongAnswer": "Project Lion",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Project Frog",
    "grade": "Hard",
    "tag": "Development"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the Hive call their home planet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fundament",
    "wrongAnswer": "Moon",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Dreadnaught",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What caused the vex to invade our universe?",
    "correctAnswer": "Crota, Son of Oryx",
    "wrongAnswer": "Ir Anuk, Deathsinger",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Collapse",
    "grade": "Hard",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What species of enemies is part of The Scorn",
    "correctAnswer": "The Fallen",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Taken",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Hive",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the Gjallahorn",
    "correctAnswer": "Feziel Crux",
    "wrongAnswer": "Ana Brax",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Vell Tarlowe",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who created the Exos?",
    "correctAnswer": "Humanity",
    "wrongAnswer": "Awoken",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Traveler",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What intelligence do the Vex have a hard time simulating, due to its complexity?",
    "correctAnswer": "Warmind",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Hive",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Ishtar Collectives",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Whoh Killed the Helium king?",
    "correctAnswer": "Savathûn",
    "wrongAnswer": "Oryx",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Xivu Arath",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What caused the owken to develop?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Collapse",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Beginning of Time",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Golden Age",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What came after the Collapse?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Dark Age",
    "wrongAnswer": "The New Beginning",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Return",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who transformed Nessus into a machine world?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Vex",
    "wrongAnswer": "The cabal",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Fallen",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who invaded Nessus after the vex transformed it into a machine world?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Fallen",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Hive",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Taken",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who founded the Guardians after the factions war?",
    "correctAnswer": "Lysander",
    "wrongAnswer": "Rezyl Azzir",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Saladin Forge",
    "grade": "Hard",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What dangerous power did the Ahamkara have that led the Great Hunt to destroy them?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wish Granting",
    "wrongAnswer": "Mind Reading",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Time Traveling",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why were the Ahamkara hunted by the last city?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wish Granting",
    "wrongAnswer": "Mind Reading",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Time Traveling",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What Titan fought the battles of Twilight gap?",
    "correctAnswer": "Saint-14",
    "wrongAnswer": "Zavala",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Saladin Forge",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the Hive call their home planet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Moon",
    "wrongAnswer": "Earth",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Dreadnaught",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who attacked the Last City in the Battle of Burning Lake?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Hive",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Fallen",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Taken",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Crota get banished by Oryx?",
    "correctAnswer": "Opening a Rift",
    "wrongAnswer": "Having the Wrong intentions",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Not Standing in his father's name",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What weapon eventually defeated the Great Dredgen Yor?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Last Word",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Thorn",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Hawkmoon",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Oryx want revenge for the death of his son Crota?",
    "correctAnswer": "Restoring reputation",
    "wrongAnswer": "The vex destroyed his home world",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The guardians killed his son",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where does the Curse of Osiris take place?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mercury",
    "wrongAnswer": "Mars",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Venus",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for the moon in the IKELOS Core?",
    "correctAnswer": "Luna",
    "wrongAnswer": "Luno",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Luni",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name for the earth in the IKELOS core?",
    "correctAnswer": "Terra",
    "wrongAnswer": "Terro",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Terri",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the leader of the house of wolves?",
    "correctAnswer": "Skolas",
    "wrongAnswer": "Riksis",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Draksis",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Osiris' deposal, who takes over the warlock vanguard?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ikora Rey",
    "wrongAnswer": "Preadyth",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Felwinter",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What race invaded Phobos before invading Mars first?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Cabal",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Taken",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Vex",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the books of Sorrow?",
    "correctAnswer": "Oryx",
    "wrongAnswer": "Crota",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Speaker",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who made the traveler",
    "correctAnswer": "The Darkness",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Beginning of time",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Fallen",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "What event caused the Fallen to Fall?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Whirlwind",
    "wrongAnswer": "The Collapse",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "The Reaping",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where is The Reef Located?",
    "correctAnswer": "In an Astroid Belt",
    "wrongAnswer": "In Empty Space",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "On Venus",
    "grade": "Easy",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is the other living lord other than Lord Shaxx?",
    "correctAnswer": "Efrideet",
    "wrongAnswer": "Shiro-4",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Felwinter",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who operates the Cabal tank in The cerberus Vae III strike??",
    "correctAnswer": "Val Ca'aul",
    "wrongAnswer": "Val Zu'uarc",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "Val Ma'arg",
    "grade": "Hard",
    "tag": "Lore"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days after destiny's release did the vault of glass get beaten?",
    "correctAnswer": "5",
    "wrongAnswer": "4",
    "wrongAnswerToo": "6",
    "grade": "Medium",
    "tag": "Mechanics"
  }
]
